## MARK FRANCIOSE

## **WEB DEVELOPER**

#### **SUMMARY**

At a young age, I was nominated by my peers to take a leadership position in the Union at my last company. I have gained invaluable experience leading people and I am very confident in my ability be placed into a difficult situation and find a viable and efficient solution. I'm looking forward to joining a team that is dynamic, fast-paced, and solving tough problems through code.

#### CONTACT

 $\bigvee$ 

in linkedin.com/in/markfran/

markfranciose

#### **SKILLS**

**FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT:** Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS, Javascript, React Native, Test Driven Development

#### **ORGANIZATIONAL LEADERSHIP:**

Strategic Planning, Leadership Development, Project Management

### **EDUCATION**

Dev Bootcamp Full Stack Development 2017

Purdue University
Political Science and Government 2007

## **PROJECT**

#### Habitual Aug 2017 to Current

- Project leader for a one week sprint. Built a native mobile productivity app with a React Native and a Rails API back end.
- Helps a user maintain healthy habits and visualizes their progress. Interactions with the app's notification take only 1 second.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Dev Bootcamp Chicago, IL

#### Full Stack Development

May 2017 to Aug 2017

- Completed a 19 week immersive full stack web development course with 1100 + hours of solo and pair programming
- Worked on numerous projects demonstrating agile, test-driven development and good git workflow

## Pension Representative

UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL -

Mar 2016 to May 2017

- Improved funding status of \$2.1 billion dollar multi-stakeholder pension fund
- Created data and analysis, developed website for member use
- Developed and gave multimedia presentations.

# Contract Negotiator UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL ·

Apr 2012 to Mar 2016

- Strengthened agreements between key employers (notably McCormick Place and United Center)
- Succeeded working with a variety of different groups, such as city officials, operators, and local management
- Led sizable teams and projects under tight deadlines

## Organizer / Organizing Trainer UNITE HERE Local 1 - Chicago, IL -

Mar 2008 to Apr 2012

- Trained numerous junior organizers
- Developed and recruited new members